<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.evepreview.manager</id>

  <name>EVE Preview Manager</name>
  <developer id="io.github.h0lylag">
    <name>h0lylag</name>
  </developer>
  <summary>Utility for EVE Online multiboxing with real-time previews and hotkeys</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      EVE Preview Manager is a lightweight utility designed to enhance the EVE Online multi-boxing experience.
    </p>
    <p>Key features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Live Previews: Real-time thumbnails of all running clients.</li>
      <li>Rapid Switching: Robust hotkey support to instantly switch focus between clients.</li>
      <li>Customization: Configurable font, borders, colors, size, opacity, and more</li>
      <li>Profiles: Save and load multiple configurations on the fly for different setups</li>
    </ul>
    <p>NOTE: This application is not affiliated with CCP Games.</p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.evepreview.manager.desktop</launchable>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <url type="homepage">https://epm.sh/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/h0lylag/EVE-Preview-Manager/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/h0lylag/EVE-Preview-Manager</url>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://epm.sh/assets/images/appearance.png</image>
      <caption>Appearance settings</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://epm.sh/assets/images/hotkeys.png</image>
      <caption>Hotkey settings</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://epm.sh/assets/images/characters.png</image>
      <caption>Character settings</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.6.1" date="2026-01-13">
      <description>
        <p>Fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed previewing custom sources launched via Steam/Proton that could cause crashes.</li>
          <li>Fixed window re-detection for minimized clients to correctly preserve character settings, cycle group state, and preview rendering.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.0" date="2026-01-12">
      <description>
        <p>New:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Automated Backups: EPM now automatically backs up your config. Backups are compressed (1-2Kb each) to keep storage impact minimal. Automatically prunes the oldest files. Manual backups are preserved indefinitely.</li>
          <li>Custom Source Settings: Integrated sources into cycle groups, added per-source hotkeys, and per-source visual overrides.</li>
          <li>Cycle Groups: Added new option (off by default) that resets the cycle order to the beginning of the list when swapping between separate cycle groups.</li>
          <li>Logging: Added --debug flag for troubleshooting and reduced standard log verbosity to keep the output less cluttered.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Custom Sources: Resolved issues with preview persistence, positioning, auto-detection logic, and borders not being applied.</li>
          <li>Overrides: Fixed a bug where per-character override settings (like static backgrounds) would fail to persist after a character logged out and back in.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.5.0" date="2025-12-24">
      <description>
        <p>New Features:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Expanded cycle groups: Profiles now support multiple independent cycle groups, enabling cycling through multiple groups of characters with separate hotkeys.</li>
            <li>Custom Sources: Experimental support for adding and previewing custom windows.</li>
            <li>Preview Toggle: New hotkey to temporarily disable or enable thumbnail previews.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.4.0" date="2025-12-20">
      <description>
        <p>New Features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Static Mode: A new per-character override that allows you to use a solid color for the thumbnail background instead of a live preview.</li>
        </ul>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a setting to disable/enable the "MINIMIZED" overlay text when using the "Minimize EVE clients when switching focus" feature.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Fixed:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a bug where inactive client borders were not rendered until the client was focused at least once before.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.2" date="2025-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>Other:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated AppStream metainfo for Flathub submission</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.1" date="2025-12-18">
      <description>
        <p>Other:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Preparations for Flathub and Arch AUR submissions</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.3.0" date="2025-12-16">
      <description>
        <p>New Features:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Tabbed GUI: Rearranged the GUI to use a tabbed structure for settings components.</li>
          <li>Inactive Client Borders: Customizable border color and thickness for inactive clients.</li>
          <li>Advanced Character Management:</li>
          <li>Aliases: Create custom names (e.g., "Main", "Super") for previews.</li>
          <li>Visual Overrides: Configure border color, text color, and size on a per-character basis.</li>
          <li>Load Profile Hotkey: Instantly load a specific profile via hotkey.</li>
          <li>Temporary Cycle Skip: Hotkey to temporarily skip a character in the cycle group (resets on refresh/swap).</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Tweaks:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Flexible Character Hotkeys: Per-character hotkeys now work even if not in the cycle group.</li>
          <li>Enforced XWayland: The app now enforces X11/XWayland mode to ensure reliable hotkeys without the user being in the input group.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <supports>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </supports>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

</component>
